hey guys I'm excited to show you my new
gym so I just moved in a new house here
in Phoenix and I've equipped an awesome
garage gym and I want to show it off
here so um the first thing I want to
show you is I got an HD TV mounted here
I'll usually have some sports going on
in the background while I work out or
I'll have like a movie um Like Gladiator
showing or something like that CU I have
hooked up to uh my Condor system with my
my internet provider uh and cable
service provider so I have like aund
movies recorded that I can watch um I've
got a nice stereo system
here and a computer if I'm doing any
research this computer is hooked up to
the Internet it's hooked up to all my
sports science equipment um and so I can
conduct research out here um this is
kind of
neat I've got a little fridge
here stacked with Powerade Zero uh these
are like the little things that make
your garage gym really cool moving on
cyx leg press this is the most
comfortable leg press there is in
existence I'm made sure to get this
because uh it just feels like it was
like designed for the human body this is
my favorite leg press machine it's they
call it the squat press from cyx but
it's my
favorite um what's cool is I've got a
heater in here too and like here's a fan
and I also have air conditioning over
there so I installed that AC unit
um in in Phoenix Arizona it gets really
hot in the summer so this way I can have
it at like you know 76 de or
whatever um here's a 45° hyper from
Elite
FTS this one has a Sumo base it's my
favorite 45° back extension CU it's got
a Sumo base it's got these band pegs so
you can use band resistance or you can
use you know like
dumbbells okay right here I've got a
glut ham raay glute ham developer from
this is also from Elite FTS and this is
my favorite glute ham developer out
there and I've use different ones that
suck compared to this one what I like
about this one is this foot plate raises
up high you want your feet to be high in
relation to the pad if you're Advanced
the lower this goes if I move this down
it becomes easier but the higher up that
I go it's more
challenging now I use this for glute ham
raises but I can also use it for back
extensions if I move this out so I can
move this all the way back and then I
can do back extensions with a band cuz
here's the Band F I can also use
dumbbell or a combination of both and I
can sit my butt here and look upwards
with my feet through here and do
straight leg
sit-ups okay moving
on here I've got equalizers I use this
for only one exercise I do feet uh
elevated in inverted rows off of this
but with my clients I will have them do
modified inverted rows you could use a
TRX for this as well but I like using
this it's really convenient here's a
single leg squat stand this I got from
perform better you just drape your leg
over it and you can hold on to dumbbells
or barbell and do Bulgarian split
squats um here's my little box of
goodies got different things in here for
example here's a slingshot I really like
this for training the top end for bench
press see for bench press you can use
bands or chains but that slingshot comes
across your chest and it's elastic so it
stretches as you come down so it helps
slingshot the weight up to here and then
you've got to take over and lock it out
so I like that uh it's just a cool tool
for over overloading the top end I
actually love my ab mat I do crunches
off of this it's my favorite ab exercise
and I'll just put my low back over this
and move mostly in the thoracic spine
really go slow and control the Ecentric
it works really really
well
um easy curl
bar lot of people don't like doing curls
but I like having training my biceps so
I found that the easy bar is easier on
my my uh forearms than the straight
bar um I use this seated row handle I
use this over here I will uh I will
actually put a band because I don't have
a seated row so I will actually put I'll
hook a band like this and put this just
hook it like this and I'll come back and
sit on the box from here and do seated
rows works really well for those of you
who don't have a seated row and like to
do different rowing exercises it's it
very a way to do them and it overloads
the overloads this squeezing portion so
it's very
effective adjustable bench uh this is
the first bench that I ever had people
do hip thrusts off of like almost eight
years ago so it's very sentimental I
want to keep it dumbbells ranging from 5
lb all the way up to 100 lb here I've
got chains um I don't ever like doing
band squats but chain squats are pretty
cool I'll just Loop that to each end of
the barbell when I do squats to overload
the top portion here's my squat stands
so here I do my squats my front squats
my military press pause squats things
like that um and I actually prefer to
have squat stands over a power rack as
long as you have bumper plates because
the bumper plates if you were to stall
out you can just drop it but I don't
fail too often on squats so um anyway
this is nice because I got this big open
area for deadlifting and it's kind of
the center piece I made these at Home
Depot I just had them cut the plywood
into squares and then I glued them all
together so these are glued I use wood
glue so this is about 3 and 1/2 in high
that's my favorite height some people
like 3 in some people like 4 in but I
will just put the weight up on there and
do block PS it's a different feel than
regular de
and then here I've got my deadlift lever
and here I will do my deadlifts my Sumo
deadlifts um and then
uh got a chalk bin right here so I can
chalk up my hands and this has the
different bands on them so I use these
bands for seated rows or for uh when I
do um hip Thruster over here but I'll
use these bands here I'll just put them
on my knees and do different type of
side steps or walking like monster walks
Sumo walks things like that I'll use two
two blacks but I have the blue and the
black for different
clients um here I've got my heavy CLE
Bells I've got the 106 pounder and the
203 pounder now I do Swings with these
I'll do swings but my top my best
clients can actually deadlift this my
females my best female clients they will
deadlift this and I like it's very
natural deadlift because their arms can
go in between their legs and it's a
little bit higher so it's a really
simple
deadlifting uh motion to teach I'll
teach him with this guy move him up to
that over
time okay moving
on um this is my tripod for my camera
I've got a sink here as well this is
convenient um here I've got a A Hammer
Strength row machine and this is my
favorite rowing machine kind of like my
my the cyx uh squat press this Hammer
Strength ISO row it is so comfortable
for me it is just the perfect grow
machine and you've got all these
different handles so I can go pronated
neutral I could go wide grip you know
lower grip I can you know uh I you can
do one arm at a time or two arms at a
time but to me this is just the most
comfortable rowing machine ever invented
and I just it it starts narrower so your
hands are narrow close together and as
you pull back it spreads outwards so you
end up right here and I think that's why
I one of the reasons why I feel it so
much in my lats but this is my favorite
rowing
machine okay moving on here uh this is
my favorite glute exercise the hip
thrust and after seven years of s and a
half years of doing hip thrust I feel
like I finally got the perfect system
for hip thrusting so uh I will do twice
a week I'll do band and twice a week
I'll do
barbell uh well lately I've just been
doing three total days a week of hip
thrust but if I do
bands I just lookt this through
here like
this and then uh
get this centered over my body so if I
do
bands I'll just kind of climb up like
this dig my elbows in and just thrust
upwards so here's how I do the bands you
know just like that okay
but I like doing both bands and barbell
throughout the week and this is where
this system is so convenient I bought a
squat sponge off of Amazon
and I see this here these mats these are
the same mats as the foot pad off the
hip Thruster so I just got two extra
ones so if I didn't have these mats and
I went to roll it see here it hits my
legs it would hit my thighs but since I
have these
mats just go like this and I roll it up
right over it so it comes right up and
then I can do my hip thrust it's the
perfect elevation so comfortable this is
a thick bar pad so it really cushions
the hips and I feel like this is the
perfect height to get the most out of
your hip to dress
so this is my favorite glute training
station now here's where I do my bench
press and my close grip
bench uh out of this rack here so just
put the bar here I also can do like band
standing hip thrust here which I I
showed in a recent video I do my
chin-ups here I like neutral grip the
most I also have dip attachments so I
can do dips if I want but I don't do
many dips
anymore
um moving on here's my lap pull down
machine now what I really like about
this is that I bought this special
attachment here this is a MAG maximum
Advantage
grip and it's so comfortable it just
changes things when you have this grip
so when I come down here I will you know
it's just so
uh I can I can fin angle this do I get a
full stretch and I come down and it's
just so comfortable having this grip um
compared to other grips just a really
smooth feel to
it
okay over here I've
got this is
a glute ham roller that I got from
sorex you lay down on the ground you put
your heels in here and you do hamstring
curls sliding up and down so it's a very
stable these are roller blade wheels and
it's a very stable way to do the sliding
hamstring curls
um here is a hex bar for hex bar or trap
bar deas so here's a Grappler I got from
Westside now this is similar to a land
mine unit but what I like about this is
I also bought this
single uh handle from perform better so
I can hook this up to the grappler and
hook a barbell up and I can do like
single leg braced rdls with heavy weight
and if I brace I can use really heavy
weight with them good
exercise okay moving
on here I've got a seated shoulder press
I like doing standing military and I
also like doing seated so I can do
seated with dumbbells or with barbell
here I have the barbell hooked up so uh
I do my like seated front shoulder press
here moving on this is my reverse hyper
now this I got from um I think I got it
from Elite FTS but it's a Westside
reverse hyper and I got this back in the
day this is my favorite one um they've
made Modern more modern ones with like
the roller the pendulum but I just like
having the regular scrap here it's my
favorite way to do them and
um I uh I also do them so here I will
just wrap my legs through here come over
and do my reverse hypers this way but I
also will grab the ERX balance pad which
uh I will put down here and have people
get kneeling and kick backwards against
the pendulum so it comes up and down
it's like a weighted a weighted way to
do quadruped hip extensions or quadruped
donkey kicks very effective glute
exercise now I bought these ankle
weights originally I wanted to do
different type of like quadruped ankle
weight glute exercise like the way that
the Brazilians do but I actually don't
like it for that if I want to train my
glutes I just do band or barbell hip
thrust but I do love these ankle weights
because they go up to 20 lbs these are
heavy duty ones they're TKO I got these
off Amazon and I will strap this in and
I will do uh like marching um I'll just
lift one leg up and lift the next and I
do
marching um hip flexor raises if I do a
set of 20 with this it's really
effective but I also will do abductions
like this and it's very effective so
those are my two favorite uh Hip Flex or
hip hip EX exercises that I do with
these ankle
weights here I've got a bathroom in here
kind of
cool and then
finally this is an incline press I
bought this off of a an old uh my I
trained at World Gym back in the day and
they were switching out all their
equipment and I naed this for a couple
hundred bucks and here I've got a water
cooler so
anyway I hope you enjoy the video I hope
you enjoy the the the the gym the garage
gym to me it's like my dream home gym I
feel like I can get a better workout
here than I can at most
gyms however just encourage some of you
I started out when I was 24 years old
this is the first thing that I bought
this power Tech this crappy power Tech
um you know power rack here this cage
along with this power Tech bench here I
bought this 14 years ago and the first
thing that I bought that in a a barbell
and some plates and then I remember I I
bought this
uh these 25 lb dumbbells were the first
dumbbells that I
bought and I had some dumbbells and
little by little I just kept buying more
things and after 14 years now I've got
this so hopefully that inspires some of
you to start building up because it's so
empowering to have your own home gym I
can listen to whatever music I want I
can have sports going on in the
background I can have um you know
whatever temperature I want there's no
waiting for equipment I can have my
favorite equipment in here and uh you
can get a better workout than you can at
standard commercial
gyms um so if some of you on the fence
just start little by little buy one
thing buy the next thing you'll be glad
you did anyway thank you for watching